Register of the Clovis E. Byers Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Clovis E. Byers papers
1917-1961
64016
Hoover Institution Archives
47 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 3 envelopes, 4 album boxes, 1 oversize folder, 1 motion picture film reel, 1 phonotape reel (28 linear feet)
Correspondence, memoranda, diaries, speeches and writings, clippings, personnel records, and audiovisual material, relating to the Pacific Theater during World War II, the Army of Occupation in Japan, the Korean War, and the North Atlantic Treaty Organization command in Europe.
Byers, Clovis E., 1899-1973
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
The collection was acquired by the Hoover Insitution Archives in 1964
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1899 November 5 Born, Columbus, Ohio
1917-1918 Attended Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio
1920 Graduated from West Point and was commissioned a Second Lieutenant in the Cavalry
1920-1921 Student, Cavalry School
1923-1924 Student, Signal School
1925 Promoted to First Lieutenant
1930-1931 Student, Special Advanced Equitation Course, Cavalry School, Fort Riley, Kansas
1931-1932 Served with 8th Cavalry Regiment
1932-1933 Commanding officer, Cadet Company, United States Military Academy
1935 Promoted to Captain
1940 Promoted to Major
1941 Promoted to Lieutenant Colonel (temporary)
1942 Promoted to Colonel and Brigadier General (temporary). Awarded Distinguished Service Cross, Silver Star, and Purple Heart
1943 Promoted to Lieutenant Colonel, United States Army
1944 Awarded Oak-Leaf Cluster to the Silver Star, Legion of Merit, Bronze Star Medal, Oak-Leaf Cluster to the Silver and Bronze Star, and Air Medal
1945 Promoted to Major General (temporary), United States Army. Awarded Distinguished Service Medal and Second Oak-Leaf Cluster to the Bronze Star
1946 Awarded Military Merit Medal
1947 Awarded Commander of the Order of the British Empire (CBS)
1948 Promoted to Brigadier General, United States Army. Awarded Oak-Leaf Cluster to Legion of Merit and French Legion of Honor Officer Rank
1952 Promoted to Major General, United States Army
1954-1955 Deputy Commandant, National War College, Washington, D.C.
1955 Promoted to Lieutenant General, United States Army
1955-1957 Commandant, NATO Defense College, Paris
1957-1959 Special Assistant to the Defense Secretary
1958 President, Alumni Association, National War College, Washington, D.C.
1959 Retired from the United States Army
1973 December 13 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
The Clovis E. Byers Papers, acquired in 1964, consist of correspondence, memoranda, diaries, speeches and writings, clippings, personnel records, and audio-visual material, relating to the Pacific Theater during World War II, the Army of Occupation in Japan, the Korean War, and the North Atlantic Treaty Organization command in Europe.
The Correspondence, identified as Byers' personal file, includes official correspondence, letters exchanged with friends and colleagues in the military, letters Byers wrote to his family from overseas, and Byers' personal business correspondence.
The bulk of the materials included in the Military File originated from Byers' various assignments with the army. His trips to Korea, the Philippines, Japan, and Europe resulted from his military duties and his association with the NATO Defense College. The Photographs also reflect his assignments in the Pacific, the Philippines, Japan, Korea, and Europe.
As required by law, security-classified materials have been removed from the collection until they can be declassified by government officials.
Arrangement
Arranged into nine series: Biographical File, Correspondence, Speeches and Writings, Diaries and Appointment Books, Military File, Oversize Materials, Photographs, Sound Recordings and Motion Pictures.
North Atlantic Treaty Organization.; Roosevelt, Eleanor (Roosevelt), 1884-1962.; United States. Army. Army, 8th.; United States. Army. Corps, X.; United States. Army. Officers.; Japan--History--Allied occupation, 1945-1952.; Korean War, 1950-1953.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Pacific Ocean.
- Biographical File, 1926-1959. (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Article, awards, bank statements, biographical note, citations, clippings, correspondence, historical records, list, press release, and miscellany relating to Clovis Byers' personal life and professional accomplishments, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Article, "Brothers in Arms: Our War Story," about Clovis Byers and others by the editors, Blue and White, 1943 April. (Folder 1: 1)
    Printed copy
  - Awards, 1943 and undated. (Folder 1: 2)
    List of awards and decorations, undated; printed announcements in radio bulletin, Government Press Foreign Service, Department of State Division of Current Information. Printed copy; the Phi Gamma Delta; and the Ohio State University Monthly, 1943
  - Bank statements, 1946-1948 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Biographical note, undated (Folder 1: 4)
  - Citations, 1944-1951 and undated. (Folder 1: 5)
    2nd Battle Group, 60th Infantry, Order of the Go Devils, undated; "for exceptionally meritorious conduct in the performance of outstanding services in New Guinea," 1944 November 24; Air Medal for "meritorious achievement while participating in aerial flights in the Philippine Islands," 1945 April 29; and 17th Infantry, Order of the Buffalo, 1951 October 24
  - Clippings
    - General
      - Undated (Folder 1: 6)
      - 1942-1943 (Folder 1: 7)
      - 1951-1952 (Folder 1: 8)
    - New Guinea
      - Undated (Folder 1: 9)
      - 1942-1945 (Folder 1: 10)
  - Family file
    - Certificate of baptism for Clayton Byers, Cadet Chapel, New York, 1941 October 26 (Folder 1: 11)
    - Correspondence
      - General
        - Undated (Folder 1: 12)
        - 1926-1941 (Folder 1: 13)
        - 1942/1943 (Folder 1: 14)
        - 1944-1958 (Folder 1: 15)
      - Army and Navy Club, 1940-1958. (Box-folder 2: 1)
        Includes a booklet stipulating by-laws, 1955
      - Bishop of Rockhampton, 1944 (Folder 2: 2)
      - National War College, 1957-1959. (Folder 2: 3)
        Relates primarily to the activities of the alumni association. Includes a report on the final presentations, Class of 1957-1958, and Clovis Byers' letter to Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1959, and letter from Robert D. Murphy, to Clovis Byers, 1958
  - Historical file, 1945-1947. (Folder 2: 4)
    Collection of materials about important events during Byers' period of service
  - List of names of personal acquaintances, Undated (Folder 2: 5)
- Press release by Howard Handleman about Byers' promotion to the position of Senior Military Adviser to the Secretary of Defense for International Security Affairs, 1957 July 11 (Folder 2: 6)
  - Miscellany, 1943-1952 (Folder 2: 7)
- Correspondence, 1917-1959.
  Byers' personal file of letters exchanged with military personnel, family and friends, and others. Arranged in Files A ? H, thereunder numerically by folder number. Each numbered folder includes a list of letters in that folder. Additional personal letters from Byers to his family follow File H
  - File A. Personal correspondence ? General Byers
    - Number 1, 1927-1944 (Folder 2: 8-15)
    - Number 2, 1943-1944 (Folder 2: 16)
    - Number 2, 1943-1944. (Box-folder 3: 1-6)
      Includes letters from the Philippines
    - Number 3, 1944-1945. (Folder 3: 7-10)
    - Number 4, 1945. (Box-folder 4: 1-5)
    - Number 5, 1945-1946. (Folder 4: 6-10)
      Includes letters from Yokohama, Japan
    - Number 6, 1946. (Box-folder 5: 1-6)
    - Number 7, 1945/1946. (Folder 5: 7-10)
      Contains Byers' letter to Albert C. Wedemeyer, 1946 July 29, and letters relating to personal finances
    - Number 7, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 6: 1-3)
    - Number 8, 1946-1947 (Folder 6: 4-9)
    - Number 9, 1947 (Folder 6: 10)
    - Number 9, 1947 (Box-folder 7: 1-5)
    - Number 10, 1947. (Folder 7: 6-10)
      Letters to family and friends
    - Number 11, 1947. (Box-folder 8: 1-2)
    - Number 12, 1955. (Folder 8: 3)
      Replies to letters of congratulations
    - Number 13, 1955. (Folder 8: 4-5)
      Letters of congratulations
  - File B. Personal correspondence ? General Byers
    - Number 1, 1917-1932. (Folder 8: 6-9)
      Personnel records
    - Number 2, 1932-1937 (Folder 8: 10-12)
    - Number 2, 1932-1937 (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - Number 3, 1936-1939 (Folder 9: 2)
    - Number 4, 1939-1942. (Folder 9: 3)
      Investment and insurance records
    - Number 5, 1940-1942. (Folder 9: 4-5)
      Personal financial records
    - Number 6, 1941-1942 (Folder 9: 6-8)
    - Number 7, 1944. (Folder 9: 9)
      Letters to family from New Guinea
    - Number 8, 1945. (Folder 9: 10-11)
      Letters to family from the Philippines
    - Number 9, 1945-1946. (Box-folder 10: 1)
      Letters to family from Yokohama, Japan
    - Number 10, 1947 (Folder 10: 2)
    - Number 11, 1947. (Folder 10: 3)
      Letters drafted by Byers for Robert Eichelberger's signature
    - Number 12, 1947. (Folder 10: 4)
      Correspondence between Robert Eichelberger and Byers during Eichelberger's absence
  - File C. Personal correspondence ? General Byers
    - Number 1, 1947-1948 (Folder 10: 5)
    - Number 2, 1948 (Folder 10: 6-7)
    - Number 3, 1948 (Folder 10: 8-9)
    - Number 4, 1948 (Folder 10: 10)
    - Number 4, 1948 (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - Number 5, 1948 (Folder 11: 2-3)
    - Number 6, 1948 (Folder 11: 4-5)
    - Number 7, 1948 (Folder 11: 6-7)
  - File D. Personal correspondence ? General Byers
    - Number 1, 1948 (Folder 11: 8)
    - Number 2, 1948 (Folder 11: 9-10)
    - Number 3, 1948 (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - Number 4, 1948 (Folder 12: 2-3)
    - Number 5, 1948 (Folder 12: 4-5)
    - Number 6, 1948-1949 (Folder 12: 6-7)
    - Number 7, 1949 (Folder 12: 8-9)
    - Number 8, 1949 (Folder 12: 10-11)
    - Number 9, 1949 (Box-folder 13: 1-2)
    - Number 10, 1949 (Folder 13: 3)
    - Number 11, 1949 (Folder 13: 4-5)
    - Number 12, 1949 (Folder 13: 6-7)
    - Number 13, 1949 (Folder 13: 8-9)
    - Number 14, 1949 (Folder 13: 10)
    - Number 15, 1949-1951 (Box-folder 14: 1-2)
    - Number 16, 1949-1951 (Folder 14: 3)
    - Number 17, 1949-1951 (Folder 14: 4-7)
    - Number 18, 1949-1951 (Folder 14: 8-10)
    - Number 19, 1949-1951 (Box-folder 15: 1-2)
    - Number 20, 1949-1951 (Folder 15: 3-4)
    - Number 21, 1949-1951 (Folder 15: 5-6)
    - Number 22, 1949-1951 (Folder 15: 7-8)
    - Number 23, 1949-1951 (Folder 15: 9-10)
    - Number 24, 1950-1951 (Folder 15: 11)
    - Number 25 (missing) (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - Number 26, 1949-1951 (Folder 16: 2)
    - Number 27, 1949-1951 (Folder 16: 3)
    - Number 28, 1949-1951 (Folder 16: 4-7)
    - Number 29, 1949-1951 (Folder 16: 8)
    - Number 30, 1949-1951 (Folder 16: 9)
    - Number 31, 1949-1951 (Folder 16: 10)
    - Number 32, 1949-1951 (Folder 16: 11-12)
    - Number 33, 1949-1950 (Folder 16: 13)
    - Number 34, 1949-1951 (Folder 16: 14-15)
    - Number 35, 1949-1951 (Box-folder 17: 1-2)
    - Number 36, 1949-1951 (Folder 17: 3)
    - Number 37, 1949-1951 (Folder 17: 4)
    - Number 38, 1949-1951 (Folder 17: 5)
    - Number 39, 1949-1951 (Folder 17: 6-7)
    - Number 40, 1949-1951 (Folder 17: 8)
    - Number 41, 1951 (Folder 17: 9-10)
    - Number 42, 1951 (Box-folder 18: 1-2)
    - Number 43, 1951. (Folder 18: 3)
      Letters of sympathy
  - File E. Personal correspondence ? General Byers
    - Number 1, 1951-1952. (Folder 18: 4-7)
      Includes Byers' letters to friends
    - Number 2, 1951-1952 (Folder 18: 8-9)
    - Number 3, 1952 (Folder 18: 10)
    - Number 3, 1952 (Box-folder 19: 1-3)
    - Number 4, 1952 (Folder 19: 4-9)
    - Number 5, 1952. (Folder 19: 10)
      Byers' letters to Clayton
    - Number 6, 1952 (Box-folder 20: 1-4)
    - Number 7, 1952-1953 (Folder 20: 5-10)
    - Number 8, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 21: 1-4)
    - Number 9, 1953 (Folder 21: 5-12)
    - Number 10, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 22: 1-6)
    - Number 11, 1954 (Folder 22: 7-8)
    - Number 12, 1954/1955. (Folder 22: 9-12)
      Personal correspondence, A - K
    - Number 12, 1954-1955. (Box-folder 23: 1-2)
    - Number 13, 1954-1955. (Folder 23: 3-8)
      Personal correspondence, L - Z
  - File F. Personal correspondence ? General Byers
    - Number 1, 1955-1957 (Folder 23: 9)
    - Number 2, 1955-1957 (Folder 23: 10-11)
    - Number 3, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 24: 1-4)
    - Number 4, 1955-1957 (Folder 24: 5-6)
    - Number 5, 1955-1957 (Folder 24: 7-8)
    - Number 6, 1955-1957 (Folder 24: 9)
    - Number 7, 1955-1957 (Folder 24: 10-11)
    - Number 8, 1955-1957 (Folder 24: 12-13)
    - Number 9, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - Number 10, 1955-1957 (Folder 25: 2)
    - Number 11, 1955-1957 (Folder 25: 3)
    - Number 12, 1955-1957 (Folder 25: 4)
    - Number 13, 1955-1957 (Folder 25: 5)
    - Number 14, 1955-1957 (Folder 25: 6)
    - Number 15, 1955-1957 (Folder 25: 7)
    - Number 16, 1955-1957 (Folder 25: 8)
    - Number 17, 1955-1957 (Folder 25: 9)
    - Number 18, 1955-1957 (Folder 25: 10)
    - Number 19, 1955-1957 (Folder 25: 11)
    - Number 20, 1955-1957 (Folder 25: 12)
  - File G. Personal correspondence ? General Byers (Box 26)
    - Number 1, 1957-1958 (Folder 26: 1)
    - Number 2, 1956-1958 (Folder 26: 2)
    - Number 3, 1957-1958 (Folder 26: 3)
    - Number 4, 1957-1958 (Folder 26: 4)
    - Number 5, 1957-1958 (Folder 26: 5)
    - Number 6, 1957-1958 (Folder 26: 6)
    - Number 7, 1957-1958 (Folder 26: 7)
    - Number 8, 1957-1958 (Folder 26: 8)
    - Number 9, 1957-1958 (Folder 26: 9)
    - Number 10, 1958 (Folder 26: 10)
    - Number 11, 1957-1958 (Folder 26: 11)
    - Number 12, 1957-1958 (Folder 26: 12)
    - Number 13, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 27: 1)
    - Number 14, 1957-1958 (Folder 27: 2)
    - Number 15, 1957-1958 (Folder 27: 3)
    - Number 16, 1957-1958 (Folder 27: 4)
    - Number 17, 1957-1958 (Folder 27: 5)
    - Number 18, 1957-1958 (Folder 27: 6)
    - Number 19, 1957-1958 (Folder 27: 7)
    - Number 20, 1958 (Folder 27: 8)
    - Number 21, 1958 (Folder 27: 9)
    - Number 22, 1957-1958 (Folder 27: 10)
    - Number 23, 1957-1958 (Folder 27: 11)
    - Number 24, 1958 (Folder 27: 12)
    - Number 25, 1959 (Folder 27: 13)
    - Number 26, 1958-1959 (Folder 27: 14)
    - Number 27, 1958-1959 (Folder 27: 15)
    - Number 28, 1959 (Folder 27: 16)
    - Number 29, 1958-1959 (Folder 27: 17)
    - Number 30, 1959 (Folder 27: 18)
    - Number 31, 1958-1959 (Folder 27: 19)
    - Number 32, 1958-1959 (Folder 28: 1)
    - Number 33, 1959 (Folder 28: 2)
    - Number 34, 1959 (Folder 28: 3)
    - Number 35, 1958-1959 (Folder 28: 4)
    - Number 36, 1959 (Folder 28: 5)
    - Number 37, 1959 (Folder 28: 6)
    - Number 38, 1959 (Folder 28: 7)
    - Number 39, 1958-1959 (Folder 28: 8)
    - Number 40, 1958-1959 (Folder 28: 9)
    - Number 41, 1958-1959 (Folder 28: 10)
    - Number 42, 1958-1959 (Folder 28: 11)
    - Number 43, 1959 (Folder 28: 12)
    - Number 44, 1959 (Folder 28: 13)
    - Number 45, 1959 (Folder 28: 14)
  - File H. Letters of invitation
    - Number 1, 1946-1947 (Folder 28: 15-19)
    - Number 1, 1947 (Box-folder 29: 1-3)
    - Number 2, 1947-1948 (Folder 29: 4-6)
    - Number 3, 1952-1953 (Folder 29: 7-8)
    - Number 4, 1953 (Folder 29: 9-10)
    - Number 5, 1954 (Box-folder 30: 1-2)
  - Personal letters of Byers to his family from Yokohama, Japan, 1945-1946. (Folder 30: 3)
    See also box 45 and 47 for materials relating to surrender of Japan and File B for additional personal letters
  - Miscellany, 1948-1949 (Folder 30: 4)
- Speeches and Writings, 1946-1959.
  Articles, lectures, notes, remarks, statement, transcripts of speeches, and a radio talk, arranged chronologically
  - General, 1948-1951
    - Byers' personal file of speeches and notes, 1948, and suggested topics for talks, undated. Includes speaker's policy guide, 1949 (Folder 30: 5)
    - Collection of speeches, 1950-1951.
      Typescript
      - Book I (Folder 30: 6)
      - Book II (Folder 30: 7)
  - Speech, untitled and undated. (Folder 30: 8)
  - Speech, untitled, Cleveland, Ohio, undated. (Folder 30: 9)
    Typescript and handwritten note cards
  - "Airborne Operations and National Defense, 1948-1949," remarks, undated. (Folder 30: 10)
    Typescript. Includes a letter to Clarence C. Clendenen, 1966 March 14
  - "Airborne Operations of the Future," lecture, Armored School, Fort Knox, Kentucky, undated. (Folder 30: 11)
  - "Armor Expands the Airhead," article for Armored Cavalry Journal, undated. (Folder 30: 12)
  - Foreword: Course IX, NATO Defense College, Paris, undated. (Folder 30: 13)
  - Foreword for bulletin, Course X, NATO Defense College, Paris, undated. (Folder 30: 14)
  - "National Security," radio talk, undated. (Folder 30: 15)
  - Remarks, Veterans Recognition Program, Windsor, North Carolina, undated. (Folder 30: 16)
  - Statement, Sendai American-Japan Society inaugural meeting, undated. (Folder 30: 17)
  - Suggested material for talk on staff functioning and training of staff officers for staff duties, undated. (Folder 30: 18)
  - "United We Are Invincible," speech, Birmingham, Alabama, undated. (Folder 30: 19)
  - Welcoming speech, Reserve Officers' Training Corps (ROTC) and cadets, undated. (Folder 30: 20)
    Typescript outline
  - "World Sensitive Areas," address, undated. (Folder 30: 21)
  - "Observations on the Pacific Theater," address, 55th convention, Ohio Bankers Association, Ohio, 1946 May 15-16. (Folder 30: 22)
  - Address, first anniversary of the Ernie Pyle Theater, Tokyo, 1947 February 24. (Folder 30: 23)
  - "Your Job Is Important," message to the 7th I and E Training Class, 1947 March 7. (Folder 30: 24)
  - Address, graduation ceremonies, Eighth Army Replacement Training Center, 1947 March 22. (Folder 30: 25)
  - Lecture, Conference on Airborne Operations, Armed Forces Staff College, Norfolk 11, Virginia, 1947-1948. (Folder 30: 26)
  - "Six Years in Pacific," speech, 1948 May 1. (Folder 31: 1)
    Typescript outline and holograph notes
  - Speech, Ohio Department AMVETS, Cincinnati, Ohio, 1948 June 12. (Folder 31: 2)
  - Talk to officers by Clovis Byers?, 1948 June 16. (Folder 31: 3)
    Typescript notes
  - Remarks, North Carolina State Boys, 1948 June 17. (Folder 31: 4)
  - "Report on 82D," remarks, 1948 July 4. (Folder 31: 5)
    Typescript and handwritten outline
  - "Good Business in the Army," speech, meeting of the Junior Chamber of Commerce, Fayetteville, North Carolina, 1948 July 26. (Folder 31: 6)
    Typescript. Includes holograph notes and a memorandum from J. H. Harper
  - "Keeping Informed," speech, luncheon meeting, Optimist Club, Raleigh, North Carolina, 1948 August 30. (Folder 31: 7)
  - "Insurance and Its Evaluation," speech, Southern Pines Kiwanis Club, 1948 September 8. (Folder 31: 8)
    Typescript. Includes notes
  - "Responsibilities of Citizenship Today," speech, First Presbyterian Church, Fayetteville, North Carolina, 1948 September 15. (Folder 31: 9)
    Holograph outline
  - "Airborne Operations of the Future," lecture, Armed Forces Staff College, Norfolk, Virginia, 1948 October 1. (Folder 31: 10)
    Typescript. Includes several versions
  - "Airborne Operations of the Future," lecture, Engineer School, Fort Belvois, Virginia, 1949 February 8. (Folder 31: 11)
  - "Airborne Operations of the Future," lecture, Anti-Aircraft Artillery School, Fort Bliss, Texas, 1949 March 21. (Folder 31: 12)
  - "Airborne Operations of the Future," lecture, Armed Forces Staff College, Norfolk, Virginia, 1949 March 25. (Folder 31: 13)
  - Talk, 82D Airborne Division Association Convention, Cleveland, Ohio, 1949 July 5. (Folder 31: 14)
  - Speech, annual pig dinner, Phi Gamma Delta, Washington, D.C., 1950 April 28. (Folder 31: 15)
  - Remarks, Thanksgiving Day, Headquarters X Corps, Kwandae-Ri, Korea, 1951 November 22. (Folder 31: 16)
  - "Washington and National Defense," article, Daughters of the American Revolution Magazine, 1952 February. (Folder 31: 17)
  - "Obligations of the Academy and Its Graduates in the Future," speech, West Point banquet, Tokyo, 1952 March? (Folder 31: 18)
  - Remarks, Headquarters XVI Corps, 1952 May 10. (Folder 31: 19)
  - Speech, turnover ceremony, NATO Defense College, Paris, 1955 November 15. (Folder 31: 20)
  - Speech, Paris American High School, France, 1956? (Folder 31: 21)
    Typescript. Includes related materials
  - Address, German journalists, Association for Democratic Action, sponsored by NATO Information Service, 1956 January 25. (Folder 31: 22)
  - "Review of the Eighth Course," lecture, Paris, 1956 February 2. (Folder 31: 23)
  - Speech, closing ceremony, Course VIII, 1956 February 3. (Folder 31: 24)
  - Speech, opening ceremony, Course IX, 1956 February 20. (Folder 31: 25)
  - Talk, European Commandery, Military Order of Foreign Wars of the United States dinner meeting, Paris, 1956 April 17. (Folder 31: 26)
  - Talk, sunset supper, Ohio State University, Ohio, 1956 May 5. (Folder 31: 27)
  - Remarks, review of Course IX, 1956 July 26. (Folder 31: 28)
  - Speech, closing ceremony, Course IX, 1956 July 27. (Folder 31: 29)
  - Speech, opening ceremony, Course X, 1956 September 3. (Folder 31: 30)
  - Welcoming remarks, orientation, members of Course X, 1956 September 3. (Folder 31: 31)
  - Remarks, review of Course X, 1957 January 31. (Folder 31: 32)
  - Speech, closing ceremony, Course X, 1957 February 1. (Folder 31: 33)
  - Remarks, opening ceremony, Course XI, 1957 February 18. (Folder 31: 34)
  - Welcoming remarks, NATO Defense College, Paris, 1957 February 18. (Folder 31: 35)
  - Talk, Ladies Group, NATO Defense College, Paris, 1957 May 3. (Folder 31: 36)
  - Address, North Atlantic Council luncheon, 1957 May 7. (Folder 31: 37)
  - Final talk, Course XI, NATO Defense College, Paris, 1957 July 26. (Folder 31: 38)
  - Remarks, closing and turnover ceremony, NATO Defense College, Paris, 1957 July 26. (Folder 31: 39)
  - "The Free World Coalition in the Struggle," speech, National War College, Fort Lesley J. McNair, Washington, D.C., 1957 August 30. (Folder 31: 40)
  - Remarks, Armed Forces Day, St. Patrick's Church, 1958 May 11. (Folder 32: 1)
  - "The Massing of the Colors," talk, Washington Cathedral, Washington, D.C., 1958 May 25. (Folder 32: 2)
  - "Military Requirements in the Space Age: Share in America Program," remarks, Columbus, Ohio, 1958 June 3. (Folder 32: 3)
  - Speech, Veterans and Fraternal Day, sesquicentennial celebration, Mansfield, Ohio, 1958 July 17. (Folder 32: 4)
    Typescript. Includes a letter from Fred J. Tonnemacher, 1958 July 11, memorandum, and program
  - Remarks, the SACLANT Annual Review Visiting Team, Washington, D.C., 1958 July 22. (Folder 32: 5)
  - "The Armed Forces as an Element of Power," speech, NATO Defense College, Paris, 1958 September 8. (Folder 32: 6)
  - "Religious Outlook of the Military," speech, 1958 September 10. (Folder 32: 7)
  - Speech, Institute on World Affairs, Oregon State College, Oregon, 1958 November 13. (Folder 32: 8)
    Brochure, correspondence, and itinerary only
  - "The Military and the New Look in Europe," speech, Oregon State College, Oregon, 1958 November 13. (Folder 32: 9)
    Typescript. Brochure, correspondence, and itinerary only